Start simple.
Start with what you know is true.
My name is Katniss Everdeen.
My home is District 12.
I was in the Hunger Games. I escaped.
Peeta... Peeta was left behind.
Miss Everdeen?
You can't be in here.
I had a nightmare. Just five more minutes.
You need to sleep. We can help you sleep.
Just five more minutes.
No.
No, please, don't. It's just five more...
Don't touch me! Don't!
No! Get off of me!
Finnick.
I wanted to go back for Peeta and Johanna,
but I couldn't move.
They have Annie, too. They took her.
She's in the Capitol.
I wish she was dead.
I wish they were all dead and we were, too.
Miss Everdeen.
Colonel Boggs,
District 13's head of security.
I know you've been discharged,
but President Coin's
requested to meet with you first.
Is there any news?
I'm just here to escort you.
We were always told
there was nothing left of 13.
Capitol bombed the surface to rubble.
But we're military,
so we learned to survive down here.
Preparing, training.
The war never stopped for us.
There she is.
Our Girl on Fire.
Madam President, may I present you with
The Mockingjay.
What an honor it is to meet you.
You're a courageous young woman.
I know how disorienting this must be.
And I can't imagine what it's like to
live through the atrocities of those Games.
Katniss, President Alma Coin.
Please know how welcome you are.
I hope you'll find some comfort with us.
We've known loss in 13, too.
This is history. Right here at this table.
I apologize.
I wish you had more time to recover,
but unfortunately, we
don't have that luxury.
Please, have a seat.
Are you aware of what's happened?
When you fired your
arrow at the force field
you electrified the nation.
There have been riots and uprisings
and strikes in seven districts.
We believe that if we
keep this energy going
we can unify the districts
against the Capitol.
But if we don't, if we let it dissipate,
we could be waiting another 75 years
for this opportunity.
Everyone in 13 is ready for this.
What about Peeta? Is he alive?
I don't know. And I wish that I did.
But there's no way for me to contact
my operatives inside the Capitol.
The Capitol has always suppressed
communication between the districts.
But I know their system very well.
I managed to break through.
All we need now is the perfect message.
Katniss, here's what we need to do.
We need to show them
that The Mockingjay's alive and well
and willing to stand
up and join this fight.
'Cause we need every district
to stand up to this Capitol.
The way you did.
So we're gonna shoot
a series of propaganda clips,
propos, I like to call them,
on The Mockingjay.
Spreads the word that we're
gonna stoke the fire of this rebellion.
The fire that The Mockingjay started.
You left him there.
You left Peeta in that arena to die.
Katniss, there are so many...
Peeta was the one
who was supposed to live.
Miss Everdeen.
This revolution is about everyone.
It's about all of us.
And we need a voice.
Then you should've saved Peeta.
Maybe you should have
rescued the boy instead.
No.
No, listen to me.
No one else can do this but her.
This is not the girl you described.
Obviously, we need to make it personal.
Remind her who the real enemy is.
She knows who the enemy is.
That's not the issue.
Unless she's forgotten.
There's explaining and there's showing.
Let her see what the Capitol did to 12.
She can't handle it.
The Games destroyed her.
This is the only choice you have.
People don't always show up
the way you want them to, Madam President.
But that anger, that anger-driven defiance,
that's what we want.
And we can redirect it.
We need to unite these people out there
that have been doing nothing but
killing each other in an arena for years.
We have to have a lightning rod.
They'll follow her.
She's the face of the revolution.
Let her see it. Let her go home.
Send her.
I can't believe
you're going through with this.
You can say "no."
I need to see it for myself.
This way.
13 swept everything,
top to bottom so you'd be safe.
You sure you don't want me to go with you?
Yeah. I'm sure.
We'll have our eyes on you from above.
Figures.
Hey!
Come on.
Don't you wanna see Prim?
There you go. You're breakin' my heart.
Egeria!
We need to fix these lines.
I won't say "rebels."
These are senseless acts of defiance.
And I won't legitimize them.
We'll call them "criminals."
"Radicals."
Otherwise we're breaking my oldest rule.
Never let them see you bleed.
Citizens,
tonight I address all of Panem as one.
Since the Dark Days,
Panem has had
an unprecedented era of peace.
It is a peace built upon cooperation.
And a respect for law and order.
In the past weeks,
you have heard of sporadic violence
following the actions of a few radicals
in the Quarter Quell.
Those who choose this destructive path,
your actions are based on
a misunderstanding
of how we have survived. Together.
It is a contract.
Each district supplies the Capitol.
Like blood to a heart.
In return,
the Capitol provides order and security.
To refuse work
is to put the entire system in danger.
The Capitol is the beating heart of Panem.
Nothing can survive without a heart.
The criminals that kneel before you
use symbols for the purpose of sedition.
Which is why all images of The Mockingjay
are now forbidden.
Possessing them
will be considered treason.
Punishable by death.
Justice shall be served swiftly.
Order shall be restored.
To those who ignore
the warnings of history,
prepare to pay the ultimate price.
It's okay. We're okay.
We're all here now.
Buttercup!
I smuggled him in.
I got Dad.
And I got some of your herbs
from the kitchen.
They have strict rules.
I don't know what they'll do
if they find him here.
You should try to eat something.
Hello. Good evening.
And a big welcome to all in Panem.
I'm Caesar Flickerman.
And whoever you are,
whatever it is you're doing,
if you're working, put down your work.
If you're having dinner,
stop having dinner.
Because you are going to
want to witness this tonight.
There has been rampant speculation
about what really happened
in the Quarter Quell.
And here to shed a little light on the
subject for us is a very special guest.
Please welcome Mr. Peeta Mellark.
Peeta, a lot of people
feel as though they are in the dark.
Yeah, I know how they feel.
Now, so set the stage for us.
Talk us through what really happened
on that final and controversial night.
First off, you have to understand
that when you're in the Games
you only get one wish. It's very costly.
You're alive.
It costs your life.
I think it costs more than your life.
How do you mean?
What's more than your life?
I mean to murder innocent people,
that costs everything that you are.
Yes.
So you hold on to that one wish.
And that night my wish was to save Katniss.
Yes.
I should've just run off with her
earlier in the day like she'd wanted.
But you didn't. Why?
Were you caught up in Beetee's plan?
No, I was caught up trying to play allies.
And then they separated us
and that's when I lost her.
And then the lightning hit
and the whole force field around the arena
just blew out.
Yes, but, Peeta,
Katniss is the one who blew it out.
No.
You saw the footage.
No, she didn't know what she was doing.
Neither of us knew there was
a bigger plan going on. We had no idea.
- You had no idea?
- No.
All right. Well, Peeta, there are many
who find this suspicious to say the least.
It seems as though
she was part of a rebel plan.
Do you think it was part of her plan
to be almost killed by Johanna?
Or part of the plan
to be paralyzed by lightning?
No, we were not part of any rebel plan.
We had no idea what was going on.
All right. I believe you, Peeta Mellark.
Thank you.
Yeah.
And I was going to ask you to speak
about the unrest
but I think you might be too upset.
No, I can.
- Are you sure?
- Absolutely.
Thank you.
I want everyone who's watching to stop
and to think about
what a civil war could mean.
We almost went extinct once before.
And now our numbers are even fewer.
He's one of them.
Is this really what we wanna do?
He's a traitor.
Kill ourselves off?
Killing is not the answer.
I can't believe he's doing this.
Everyone needs to
lay down their weapons immediately.
Traitor!
He's not one of us!
This is treason!
Are you calling for a ceasefire?
Yeah. I am.
You're a puppet!
Hang him!
I want everyone to stop
the senseless violence.
This is not the path to change.
Traitor!
It's not the path to justice.
There can't be a ceasefire.
Not after everything Snow's done.
He could have done a lot of damage tonight.
Most districts, people are still
too afraid to join. They need the courage.
Why do you think he said that?
I don't know. Maybe he was forced.
He didn't look that bad.
Maybe he made some kind of deal
to protect you.
He's still playing the game.
No! No! No!
I'm sorry. It's just a nightmare.
That's okay. I get 'em, too.
Peeta,
will you stay with me?
Yeah.
Always.
Hey.
Can't sleep?
Tell me what's happening.
I'm good at keeping secrets.
Even from Mom.
No one hates the Capitol more than me.
And I wanna help. But I just keep thinking,
even if we win this war,
what happens to Peeta?
I know he's not safe there,
but he's definitely not safe here.
I don't think you know
how important you are to them.
If you want something,
you just have to ask.
You could demand almost anything.
They'd have to agree to it.
I should wake you up
more often, Little Duck.
Get some sleep now.
You, too.
Thank you for agreeing to meet with me.
I've decided I'll be your Mockingjay.
But I have some conditions.
Peeta and the other Tributes,
Johanna Mason and Annie Cresta,
will be rescued at the
earliest opportunity.
If and when Peeta is liberated,
he will receive
a full and unconditional pardon.
No punishment will be inflicted.
And the same goes for the other Tributes.
No.
It's not their fault
you abandoned them in the arena.
They're doing and saying
whatever they can to survive.
Individuals don't make demands in 13.
There will be a tribunal.
And a fair judgment.
Thank you.
The Victors will be granted immunity.
And you will announce that
in front of the entire population of 13.
You will hold yourself
and your government responsible
or you will find another Mockingjay.
That's it. That's her. Right there.
Isn't that who I promised you?
She wears the costume.
Gunfire in the background. A hint of smoke.
Our Mockingjay.
Madam President, we're losing ground,
because the people are losing heart.
This is worth the risk.
She's worth the risk.
Pardons, tribunals. Power of the people.
It can all be the bedrock
of the new Panem, but,
in wartime I think even the noblest of
causes can be bent a little bit. Right?
Do you have any other conditions?
My sister gets to keep her cat.
Go away.
Is it visiting hours again?
Miss Trinket,
you see this door.
It opens. From the inside.
I've told you, these are the standard
living quarters. Same as everyone.
You're not a prisoner.
You're free to join the rest of 13.
Not looking like this. Thank you very much.
We have a bigger issue
than wardrobe, Miss Trinket.
Katniss has agreed to be The Mockingjay.
That poor thing.
And your Girl on Fire is burnt out.
I need you to join this team now.
I need someone she trusts.
What about Haymitch?
He's drying out in some
facility a mile down.
Aiding rebels is not really my forte.
Miss Trinket,
your days in the Capitol are over,
no matter what happens here.
If you wanna play a prisoner of war, fine.
Stay here and rot.
I'll find someone else
to be The Mockingjay's escort.
Who?
Anyone can be replaced.
Not your Mockingjay.
There isn't a soul in this dungeon
who knows the first thing about Katniss.
You honestly believe one of these
cave dwellers is going to take my place?
No.
Good afternoon.
Thank you for interrupting your schedules.
They have already been adjusted
to compensate for the delay.
I hardly ever see children around here.
Please, check in with your unit supervisors
when you resume work.
A lot of them were lost in an epidemic
a few years ago.
I have an announcement
for the citizens of 13.
Coin lost her family, too.
Daughter and a husband.
And our welcome guests from 12.
Katniss Everdeen has consented to be
the face of our cause
to help unite the districts
against the Capitol.
In exchange,
I have promised several concessions.
First, we'll assess all opportunities
for the extraction of the Victors
held hostage in the Capitol.
Peeta Mellark,
Johanna Mason...
Finnick, I made the deal for Annie, too.
And Annie Cresta.
Once freed, they will be granted
full pardon for any and all crimes
committed against the rebel cause.
Good.
That's good, Katniss.
If Katniss Everdeen
fails to fulfill her duties
the deal will be off.
Thank you for your attention.
Please, resume your daily schedules.
Madam President.
Effie Trinket.
Welcome to 13.
Madam President, may I say you are so very
concise.
You believe that there's more to be said?
May I speak freely?
You don't appear to do anything else.
I'm only talking about salesmanship.
The thing with revolutions,
they're a tender flame.
They need to be nurtured
with a little kindling and warmth.
Bit of oxygen.
Oxygen.
One sure way to put
it out is to smother it.
Or to use up all the air in the room.
Excuse me.
You know what could use a revolution?
That hair.
Effie?
What are you doing here?
I'm a political refugee.
Plutarch rescued you?
Rescued, yes, that's what he calls it.
You and I were both in the dark.
Now I'm condemned to
this life of jumpsuits.
It is wonderful to see you again.
Can you believe this place?
I miss coffee.
I never knew anyplace could be so strict.
I mean, I thought at least in
the higher ranks there'd be some
side action.
I miss my wigs.
Luckily, I remembered that
this was all the rage when I was coming up.
You know,
everything old can be made new again.
Like democracy.
Which brings me to this.
Cinna.
He's dead, isn't he?
Yes, dear.
He made Plutarch promise
not to show you this
until you'd decided to be The Mockingjay
on your own.
He knew the risks. As we all do.
He believed in this revolution.
He believed in you.
They're beautiful.
They have it.
They have the Mockingjay outfit.
There's not much of a prep team here in 13
but we will make you
the best-dressed rebel in history.
Okay.
Bring up the lights.
Cinna's final touch.
Everyone's either gonna wanna
kiss you, kill you,
or be you.
Perfect.
Absolutely perfect.
Okay. Let's bring up the setting.
Little wind.
Okay, Katniss, we're gonna start you
down on one knee.
- Okay.
- And as you rise up,
you're gonna hold your flag in the air
and deliver your line.
And remember you've just stormed
the outskirts of the Capitol
arm-in-arm with your brothers and sisters.
Okay.
Whenever you're ready.
People of Panem, we fight, we dare, we...
Does she know the line?
I know it. I got it. I'm sorry.
- Let's do it again.
- She's warming up.
All right. With energy. Go.
People of Panem, we fight!
We dare to end this hunger for justice!
You've just been in battle!
I'm sorry. Excuse my outburst.
You've just been in battle.
Let's try it again.
Whenever you're ready.
People of Panem, we fight!
We dare to end this hunger for justice.
And that, my friends,
is how a revolution dies.
Hello, Katniss.
This how you greet an old friend?
Maybe I don't recognize you sober.
I guess it looks as bad as it feels.
People of Panem, we fight!
We dare! We end this hunger for justice!
Madam President, indulge me for a moment,
if you would.
Let's everybody think of one incident
where Katniss Everdeen
genuinely moved you.
Not where you were jealous of her hairstyle
or her dress went up in flames
or she made a halfway decent shot
with an arrow.
And not where Peeta made you like her.
No, I'd like you all to think of one moment
where she made you feel something real.
When she volunteered
for her sister at the Reaping.
Excellent example.
Okay.
I hope that wasn't important.
Okay. "Volunteer for sister."
Good. What else?
When she sang that song for little Rue.
Oh, yeah. Who didn't get choked up at that?
You know, I like you better, Effie,
without all that makeup.
Well, I like you better sober.
When she chose Rue as an ally, as well.
Yes.
Now, what do all these have in common?
No one told her what to do.
Unscripted, yes.
So maybe we should just leave her alone.
And wash her face.
She's still a girl. You made her look 35.
The opportunities for spontaneity
are obviously lacking below ground.
So what you're suggesting
is we toss her into combat?
I can't sanction putting an untrained
civilian in battle just for effect.
This is not the Capitol.
That is exactly what I'm suggesting.
Put her in the field.
No, we can't protect her.
It has to come from her.
That's what people respond to.
You want a symbol for the revolution?
She cannot be coached into it.
Trust me, I know.
Maybe there's someplace
that's less dangerous.
District 8.
They reported heavy bombing last week.
There are no military targets left.
We can't guarantee her safety.
You'll never be able
to guarantee my safety.
I wanna go.
And if you're killed?
Make sure you get it on camera.
I've made you some surprises.
Maybe you wanna try one out.
If you're gonna be
a part of Katniss' propo team,
you may as well look the part.
And this one is for you.
Plutarch wanted you to have a weapon
for the sake of the propos
but I couldn't just make you
a fashion accessory.
It's beautiful.
And look here.
Regular. Incendiary. Explosive arrows.
All color-coded.
And tell Finnick I've got a trident for him
when he's ready.
Might just cheer him up.
Let's not fire the red ones in here.
You had all of this and you just
left the districts to fend for themselves?
It's not that simple, Katniss.
We barely survived.
We weren't in any kind of shape
to launch a counterattack.
Yeah, we could've bombed the Capitol
but they would've retaliated
with at least twice the firepower.
Then what?
There would've been nobody left
to claim victory.
Sounds like exactly what Peeta said
and then you all called him a traitor.
This way, soldier.
You are camera-ready.
Doesn't your comrade look handsome?
Let's go.
Come back safe.
Quick introductions, Katniss.
These people have come a long way
to support the cause.
This is Cressida.
In my opinion one of the best
up-and-coming directors in the Capitol.
Until I up and left. Hey.
Hey.
Let's see what you can do.
All right. Be careful.
This is my assistant, Messalla.
It's an honor to meet you.
And your cameramen over there, Castor.
Hello.
And Pollux.
Let's get locked in.
You're all from the Capitol?
Plutarch got you out?
Don't expect much chitchat from him.
He's an Avox.
Capitol cut his tongue out years ago.
And, no, it wasn't any sort of rescue,
if that's what you mean.
We all fled on our own.
For this.
For you.
This has gotta be fast. In and out.
Move out.
You're alive then. We weren't sure.
Katniss, Commander Paylor, District 8.
Katniss has been recovering,
but she insisted on coming out
and seein' some of your wounded.
Well, we've got plenty of those.
We have a mass grave
a few blocks west, but,
I can't spare the manpower
to move them yet.
Hospital's past that curtain.
Any hope you can give them, it's worth it.
The Capitol's done everything they can
to break us.
Aren't you worried about
having all your wounded in one place?
I think it's better than
leaving them to die.
That's not what I meant.
Well, that's my only other option.
You can come up with another, I'm all ears.
It's right through here.
Don't film me in there. I can't help them.
Just let them see your face.
Excuse me.
Yeah. You all right?
It's okay. Here, it's okay.
I've got you. It's all right.
Katniss Everdeen?
What are you doing here?
I came to see you.
What about the baby?
I lost it.
Are you fighting, Katniss?
You here to fight with us?
I am.
I will.
Tighter.
Tighter, tighter.
Sir, some cameras were damaged
in the bombings,
but we confirmed it's her.
Zoom in.
She was visiting a makeshift hospital.
We're not sure if she's still there.
We can scramble hovercraft
from the border of 11.
We may be able to target her.
Kill the wounded.
Sir...
You wrote that speech yourself, Egeria.
Any association with the Mockingjay symbol
is forbidden.
Everyone inside that hospital
has committed treason.
Show them what it costs
to be friends with Katniss Everdeen.
Your mom's gonna be proud of you
when she sees the footage.
Will this play in the districts?
It'll be tattooed on their eyes.
There's a problem.
What kinda problem?
Incoming bombers from the north.
We need to find cover now.
There's a bunker in there.
Straight ahead and down the stairs.
Katniss!
Everdeen! Everdeen!
Gale, back away from the wall!
You okay?
Move!
They're going after something to the south.
That's towards the hospital.
They're circling back around. Come on!
That's the hospital.
They're targeting the hospital.
Help them! Help them! Get them out!
Katniss?
Katniss, can you tell everyone
what you're seeing right now?
Katniss, what do you wanna say?
I want the rebels to know that I'm alive.
That I'm in District 8
where the Capitol just bombed a hospital
filled with unarmed men,
women and children.
And there will be no survivors.
If you think for one second
that the Capitol will ever treat us fairly
you are lying to yourselves.
Because we know who they are
and what they do.
This is what they do!
And we must fight back.
I have a message for President Snow.
You can torture us and bomb us
and burn our districts to the ground.
But do you see that?
Fire is catching.
And if we burn, you burn with us!
We know who they are and what they do.
This is what they do!
And we must fight back.
You can torture us and bomb us
and burn our districts to the ground.
Plutarch's faith in you wasn't misplaced.
But do you see that?
Thank you.
Fire is catching.
Come up with me for the beginning.
And if we burn, you burn with us!
There is no progress without compromise.
No victory without sacrifice.
But I stand here with The Mockingjay
to announce that our moment has arrived.
Beetee has increased
our use of the airwaves tenfold.
We will broadcast this message
to all the districts tonight.
The Mockingjay's words inspiring everyone
to join the rebellion.
Together, we will become
an alliance to be reckoned with.
Hoorah! Hoorah! Hoorah!
You don't like hearing
a fight song at a funeral?
The more people on our side,
the closer we are to Peeta and Annie.
Yeah.
By order of President Snow
daily production quotas
have been increased.
All work shifts will be extended
by an extra two hours.
Failure to meet these quotas
will not be tolerated.
By order of President Snow
daily production quotas
have been increased.
If we burn, you burn with us!
Yeah!
- I got good news.
- What?
Coin agreed to let us hunt above ground.
He's not even afraid of us.
It's 'cause they've never
been hunted before.
It's almost not fair.
They want us back.
They asked us to head for Command.
All right. I gotta drop these off.
She was arguably our favorite Tribute.
And I think that's what
we all find most astonishing,
is that this girl was
adored in the Capitol.
And I think for you, Peeta,
it must be particularly painful.
I wish I could give this
rose to you, Katniss.
He's changed so much already.
What are they doing to him?
A sweet gesture for a girl
who has inspired such violence.
You must love her very much
to be able to forgive her.
He's shaking.
I don't think that I could.
Unless, of course, Peeta,
you think that perhaps she's being
forced into saying things
that she doesn't even understand.
Yeah. That's exactly what I think.
Even his voice is different.
I think they're using her
to whip up the rebels.
I doubt she even knows what's happening.
And what's really at stake.
Now, Peeta, I doubt that the rebels
will ever let her see this.
But if they do, what would you say to her?
To Katniss Everdeen,
the once sweet Katniss Everdeen.
I would tell her to think for herself.
Yes.
Don't be a fool, Katniss.
I know you never wanted the rebellion.
The things that you did in the Games
were never intended to start all of this.
The rebels have made you
into something that you're not.
Something that could destroy all of us.
So if you have any power or any say
in what they do or how they use you,
please, please, urge them to stop this war
before it's too late.
And ask yourself,
can you trust
the people you're working with?
Do you know what they really want?
We need to respond.
Thank you, Peeta Mellark, for these
revelations about the real Mockingjay.
Did you see what he looks like?
I saw a coward.
You don't have any idea
what he's going through.
I don't care.
I would never say what he just said.
Not if they tortured me.
Not with a gun to my head.
That is the same Peeta
that defended you at the whipping post.
No, it's not.
Now he's only defending himself.
Coin's called a meeting.
We need to respond.
When did "we" become you and Coin?
Everyone has a choice.
How can he sit there in the Capitol
and defend the people
who destroyed his home
and murdered his family?
He doesn't know.
How could he?
Nobody's seen what the Capitol did to 12.
I have to show them.
So I wanna start with you
in front of the Justice Building, okay?
Bang. First shot.
Katniss, tell us what happened here.
We were all standin' right here
watchin' the Games
when you fired that arrow.
The screens just went dark.
Nobody had any idea what happened.
Peacekeepers forced us
back into our homes.
For maybe an hour,
the town was just dead quiet.
Little past 9:00,
we heard their trucks pullin' out.
All of them. Every single Peacekeeper.
And I knew what that meant.
Me and a couple of guys from the mines,
we started pulling people from their houses
and tried to get 'em to the fence line
but a lotta people were
scared of the forest.
So they headed up onto the road.
Make a break for it that way.
Stay with Gale.
915 of us made it to the fence.
Then we watched
as bombers circled back towards the road.
They firebombed them as they ran away.
915 outta 10,000.
I should've grabbed people.
I should've dragged 'em with me.
Some of the kids I could've carried.
You saved so many people, Gale.
Without you, there would be no District 12.
Not even the memory of it.
This is where you kissed me.
I didn't think you remembered that.
I'd have to be dead to forget that.
Maybe not even then.
I knew you'd do that.
How? I didn't.
'Cause I'm in pain.
That's the only way
that I can get your attention.
Don't worry, Katniss. It'll pass.
Hey.
Yeah, that's a mockingjay.
Well, now they'll never shut up.
You want me to sing?
Are you, are you comin' to the tree?
Where they strung up a man
They say who murdered three
Strange things did happen here
No stranger would it be
If we met at midnight in the hanging tree
Are you, are you comin' to the tree?
Where a dead man called out
for his love to flee
Strange things did happen here
No stranger would it be
If we met at midnight in the hanging tree
Are you, are you comin' to the tree?
Where I told you to run
so we'd both be free
Strange things did happen here
No stranger would it be
If we met at midnight in the hanging tree
Are you, are you comin' to the tree?
Wear a necklace of hope
side by side with me
That line was originally
"necklace of rope."
I had it changed to "necklace of hope."
Wow. You are a true wordsmith.
Little on the nose, but,
of course, so is war.
Every district's seeing this?
Yes. But not the Capitol.
I designed this
signal defense system for them.
But I can't find my way through it.
Guess I did my job too well.
At the time, I was just thinking of
the science of it all.
We'll get through it.
Are you, are you comin' to the tree?
Where they strung up a man
they say who murdered three
Strange things did happen here
No stranger would it be
If we met at midnight in the hanging tree
Are you, are you comin' to the tree?
Where a dead man called out
for his love to flee
Strange things did happen here
No stranger would it be
If we met at midnight in the hanging tree
Moves and countermoves.
Katniss, you're wanted in Command.
Tonight, we've received reports
of derailed trains,
of granaries on fire,
and of a savage attack
on the hydroelectric dam in District 5.
What have they done to you?
I'm begging for restraint and decency.
We interrupt your
regularly scheduled horse manure
to bring you...
Comin' to the tree?
That's it. That's our footage.
Beetee's in.
They say who murdered three
Katniss?
He sees it. He sees our propo.
No stranger would it be...
Katniss, are you there?
Peeta.
Katniss?
Peeta, please continue.
You were telling us
about these savage attacks.
Yeah.
The attack on the dam was a callous
and inhuman act of destruction...
Where a dead man called out
for his love to flee
Think about it.
How will this end? What will be left?
No one can survive this.
No one is safe now.
Not here in the Capitol.
Not in any of the districts.
They're coming, Katniss.
They're gonna kill everyone.
And in District 13 you'll
be dead by morning.
He's warning us. That was a warning.
Yes, it was.
We have to get him
out before they kill him.
- Is there anything in the air?
- Nothing on Doppler, ma'am.
He was in the mansion.
He could have overheard something.
Possibly.
It's time for an air raid drill.
This is a code red alert.
Please, remain calm
and begin evacuation protocol.
Prim! Prim!
Proceed to your nearest stairwell
and descend to level 40.
Blast doors will be sealed in six minutes.
This is a code red alert.
Please, remain calm
and begin evacuation protocol.
Proceed in an orderly fashion
to your nearest stairwell
and descend to level 40.
Madam President, three Capitol squadrons
just entered our airspace.
How much time do we have?
They're a few seconds from range.
Prepare to scramble the fleet.
Copy that.
Open up short-range air defense.
Arm long-range missiles for counterattack.
Blast doors will be sealed in five minutes.
This is a code red alert.
Please, remain calm
and begin evacuation protocol.
Proceed in an orderly fashion
to your nearest stairwell
and descend to level 40.
Blast doors will close in four minutes.
This is a code red alert.
Please, remain calm
and begin evacuation protocol.
Proceed in an orderly fashion
to your nearest stairwell
and descend to level 40.
Blast doors will close in three minutes.
This is a code red alert.
Proceed in an orderly fashion
to your nearest stairwell
and descend to level 40.
Continue to the Supply Station
and claim one pack
for each member of your compartment.
Please keep all personal items
within your assigned area.
Be courteous to your fellow citizens.
This is a code red alert.
All citizens should be inside the bunker.
- Blast doors will close in two minutes.
- Mom!
Where's Prim?
I thought she went to find you.
She must still be on the stairs.
There's no one on the stairs.
She went back for the cat.
This is a code red alert.
All citizens should be inside the bunker.
Hey, stop! Stop!
Blast doors will close in one minute.
They hit the far edge of
the northwest quadrant. Penetrated 40 feet.
Missed the living quarters.
Only minor damage to corridors 2 and 3.
Is there any radiation?
None detected.
Doppler shows a fourth wave approaching.
- Blast doors will close in 30 seconds.
- Prim!
Prim!
Katniss!
This is a code red alert.
Blast doors will close in 15 seconds.
Get down here!
- Hurry!
- This is a code red alert.
Blast doors will close in 10 seconds.
Nine...
Eight...
Seven...
Six...
- Five...
- Hold the doors!
Four...
Three...
- Two...
- Wait! Hold the doors!
One.
You went back for the cat?
What were you thinking?
I wasn't gonna leave him behind.
I couldn't live with myself.
Blast doors are now sealed.
I know, Prim.
Let's go.
Damage to the aquifer
in the northwest quadrant.
We lost a transport corridor.
There's nothing else in the northwest.
Our surface-to-air launchers
just took a direct hit in sector 3.
Because we revealed ourselves.
They saw us firing there.
Stand down. Don't launch the fleet.
Another 12 Capitol bombers
approaching sector 3 in attack formation.
Hold fire on their approach.
What'd they hit?
Bedrock. But there's
debris in the ventilation shaft.
They're not targeting our fleet.
Or our Special Weaponry.
They don't know what we have
or where we have it.
Can you confirm
that everyone's safely in the bunker?
Already done.
Conceal all remaining anti-aircraft guns.
Seal launching pads
and ventilation corridors.
We are gonna wait this out.
This is what we're built for.
They'll seal us in here like a tomb.
The Capitol's working off
some outdated information.
I'd rather not update it for them.
Madam President, I
know it's not my place...
It's not. You're a welcome guest,
but you're out of your depth down here.
Reduce oxygen to 14 % to conserve it.
Copy that.
Take a deep breath, Mr. Heavensbee.
It's gonna be a long night.
Prim, talk about something. Anything.
They promoted me at the hospital.
I forgot to tell you.
They're training me to be a doctor.
They'd be stupid not to.
Hey.
Can I sit?
Yeah.
Snow's using Annie to punish you.
He's taunting us with them.
I didn't understand until just now
watching that stupid cat.
After your first Games,
I thought the whole romance was an act.
We all expected you
to continue that strategy.
But it wasn't until Peeta's heart stopped
and he nearly died that
I knew I'd misjudged you.
You love him.
I'm not saying in what way.
Maybe you don't even know yourself.
But anyone paying attention can see it.
How do you live with it?
I drag myself outta nightmares
and there's no relief in waking up.
But it's better not to give in to it.
Takes 10 times longer
to put yourself back together
than it does to fall apart.
Katniss? Katniss?
Come with me.
We took their best shot. Didn't we?
Yeah.
Your mother and sister okay?
Yeah, they're fine.
I need you to do something for us.
I need you to tell Panem
that we survived an attack by the Capitol
with no casualties.
And we remain fully operational.
Okay.
You should know something.
We had eight extra minutes of civilian
evacuation because of Peeta's warning.
I won't forget that.
Thank you.
So Katniss,
it's "13 is alive and well and so am I."
Katniss?
Katniss.
Never one to waste it in rehearsal, I know.
Why would they drop these?
For me.
Ready to go, Katniss?
We're gonna do this, just like District 8.
Tell me about the roses.
Tell Snow 13 is alive and well.
He's gonna kill Peeta.
Let's try again. Can you speak up?
We don't have a mic on you.
"13 is alive and well and so am I."
He's gonna kill Peeta.
I can't.
Katniss?
You can do it, Katniss.
I can't do this.
"13 is alive and well and so am I."
He's just gonna keep...
He's never gonna stop.
Cressida, we should cut the cameras.
- As long as I'm The Mockingjay.
- It's okay, Katniss.
No. He warned me. He warned me about this.
He's doing this because I'm The Mockingjay.
He's punishing Peeta to punish me.
No.
No, I can't do this.
Katniss.
Don't make me do this!
Let her go.
I gotta get out of here.
So this is the end?
I s'pose you're just gonna
hide down here forever?
I can't be The Mockingjay.
Not The Mockingjay. Just Katniss.
You know, you're the only real friend
I have down here.
I don't suppose they gave you
any kind of medication?
You're unbelievable.
Okay, but I meant what I said.
Look, the reason I'm
here is to let you know
they're rescuing Peeta.
What?
The dam went down in District 5,
took out most of the power to the Capitol.
Knocked out their signal defense.
Beetee's inside their system now,
wreaking all kinds of havoc.
A window is open to us.
How much longer? I don't know.
I guess until the Capitol
can get the power back on.
And President Coin?
You know, I can never
fully support that woman
in light of the prohibition
they have going on around this place,
but Plutarch got word
that Peeta and the others
are in the Tribute Center.
And with the power out,
Coin sees this as an opportunity.
She knows that Peeta is the Capitol's
weapon. The same way you're ours.
And as opposed to having you two
pointing at each other,
she's going to get him.
I have to go help.
Hey, whoa, kiddo. Wait.
Come on. Are you just gonna jump
outta the vent and go storm the Capitol?
Besides, it's already underway.
Six soldiers went in. Volunteer only.
And guess who was
the first brave soul to sign up.
Gale.
- Okay, Finnick?
- Yeah.
Go in the center there. Those rocks.
Castor, to left.
Pollux, you're with me.
So we'll go straight to camera.
Okay? Finnick?
Yeah.
Okay.
Take your time. Just remember
to keep talking and don't stop.
This is Finnick Odair.
Winner of the 65th Hunger Games.
And I'm coming to you from District 13,
alive and well.
We've survived an assault from the Capitol.
But I'm not here to give you recent news.
Why is Finnick doing a propo?
It's a lot more than that.
Beetee's commandeered the system.
Now that they're down to generator power
there's a more limited range of frequencies
available to them.
And I'm filling them all up with Finnick.
Not many will see it, but whoever does
will think it's another propo.
What they don't know is this broadcast
is jamming their entire system with noise.
Early defense warning,
internal communications, everything.
As long as the broadcast goes through,
our team should be able
to get in and out undetected.
The truth.
Not the myths about a life of luxury.
Not the lie about glory for your homeland.
You can survive the arena.
The moment you leave, you're a slave.
Mockingjay One, you are one minute out
from perimeter defense.
Going dark.
Stay low in case they're online.
President Snow used to sell me.
Or my body, at least.
I wasn't the only one.
If a Victor is considered desirable,
the President gives them as a reward
or allows people to buy them.
If you refuse, he kills someone you love.
Mockingjay One, you are 20 seconds
from perimeter defense.
Ten seconds.
Nine... Eight...
Seven... Six... Five...
Four... Three... Two...
One.
No response from perimeter defense.
We're inside Capitol airspace.
To make themselves feel better,
my patrons would make presents
of money or jewelry.
But I found a much more valuable
form of payment.
Secrets.
Gear up.
Switching to Night View.
There.
Command, we have visual
on the Tribute Center.
Initiating final approach.
Masks on.
See, I know all the depravity,
the deceit and the cruelty
of the Capitol's pampered elite.
But the biggest secrets are about
our good President, Coriolanus Snow.
Open the door.
Command, this is Team Leader.
Prepare to deploy gas.
We will confirm once inside.
Such a young man when he rose to power.
Such a clever one to keep it.
How, you may ask, did he do it?
One word.
Poison.
Get ready to drop.
He stopped every mutiny
before it even started.
Clear.
Clear. Command, we're inside.
Heading toward target number one.
Cell P45 lower level 2C.
Gas.
There are so many mysterious deaths
to adversaries.
Even to allies who were threats.
Snow would drink from the same cup,
to deflect suspicion.
But antidotes don't always work,
which is why he wears roses
that reek of perfume.
Help cover the scent of blood from sores
in his mouth that will never heal.
Gale.
But he can't hide the scent
of who he really is.
He kills without mercy.
He rules with deception and fear.
His weapon of choice is the only thing
suited to such a man.
Poison. The perfect weapon for a snake.
What is this place?
- Beetee?
- I'm losing them.
Powering back up.
Ma'am, the Capitol air defense system
is rebooting. It's coming back online.
Must be diverting power
from another source.
And filtering transmissions.
Another 60 seconds and we'll be cut off.
Madam President,
should we call back the hovercraft?
Broadcast me.
If Snow's watching this, maybe
he'll let the signal in, if he sees me.
Put me on the air so he can see me.
Yes. Yes.
Put her on.
Can we do this? Can we still get in?
Yes. For the moment.
The line's open. He will only see you.
Okay, Katniss, go.
President Snow?
President Snow. It's Katniss.
There's no guarantee he's even watching.
I know, but he might be.
President Snow, I need to speak with you.
Are you there?
President Snow, it's Katniss.
Can you hear me?
I need to speak with you.
President Snow, it's Katniss.
President Snow, are you there?
Can you hear me?
President Snow...
Miss Everdeen. What an honor.
I don't imagine you're calling
to thank me for the roses.
I never asked for this.
I never asked to be in the Games.
- Boggs? Come in. Boggs?
- I never asked to be The Mockingjay.
Just wanted to save my sister.
And keep Peeta alive.
Come in. Boggs?
Please, just let him go.
And I will stop being The Mockingjay.
I will disappear.
You will never have to see me ever again.
Miss Everdeen.
- Boggs, come in.
- You couldn't run from this...
Copy.
Any more than you could have run
from the Games.
Command, I need a situation report.
Boggs, we're running out of time. Hurry.
Let's move.
Please.
You've won.
You've already beaten me.
Release Peeta. And take me instead.
We're long past the opportunity
for noble sacrifice.
Then tell me what to do.
I've always kept my promises, haven't I?
You said you didn't want a war.
And that's just what's happened.
I told you what a fragile thing peace was.
And still, like a child,
you took pleasure in breaking it.
I know what you are.
I know you can't see past
your narrowest concerns.
But please, Miss Everdeen.
I doubt you know what honesty is anymore.
Command, we're at the first target.
Preparing to extract Peeta.
Will confirm when he's in hand.
Mockingjay One,
prepare hovercraft for evac.
You asked me to convince you
that I was in love with Peeta.
Haven't I at least done that?
Miss Everdeen,
it's the things we love most
that destroy us.
I want you to remember that I said that.
Don't you think I know your friends
are in the Tribute Center?
Cut them off.
- What happened?
- Boggs, come in.
What happened?
Boggs, come in. Do you read me?
- He knows that they're in there. It's a trap.
- Katniss, hold it.
We have to get a hold of them.
We have to tell them to get out. He knows.
There's no signal. We can't contact them.
No. Haymitch, he knew the whole time.
He was taunting me.
- No, Haymitch. They're in there.
- No, we don't know that.
Did I lose them both tonight?
Did I lose them? I lost them both. No! No!
There's no news.
I'm sorry.
It's the worst torture in the world.
Waiting, when you know
there's nothing you can do.
Especially for people like us.
But whatever strength, courage,
madness,
keeps us going,
you find it, at times like these.
You have it, soldier.
It's what's kept you alive all this time.
And it won't fail you now.
They're back.
I don't want that.
Johanna.
Finnick!
Annie? Annie!
You're safe. You're safe.
Gale!
Are you okay?
What? What is it?
I don't get it.
Every gun was back online and on us
and we flew right past them.
They let us go.
He's in there.
Gas we used on the guards knocked
him out, too, but it's wearing off now.
You should be there when he wakes up.
Thank you.
Peeta.
Peeta!
Peeta! Get off! Get off of her!
Let go!
No, Katniss. No, you're swollen.
Don't touch.
No, no, no. Calm down. You're okay.
Tell her she's awake.
Don't try to talk. Peeta's okay. I promise.
I just had to get him off you.
It's called hijacking.
We don't know how long
the Capitol's been doing this to Peeta.
It's fear conditioning.
Enhanced with tracker jacker venom.
You were stung your first Games.
Remember?
The venom puts the subject
in a dissociative state.
And they torture him.
With shocks and beatings,
and strip down his identity.
And then all of that suffering and fear
is redirected.
Associated with other memories
or a person.
They can change his memories of Katniss?
To make her seem life-threatening.
They turned him into a weapon, Katniss.
To kill you.
But you can reverse it?
The fear is the most difficult thing
to overcome.
We're hardwired to remember fear best.
It's new terrain.
But we've put together a team.
I'm optimistic.
Good evening.
Yesterday, I authorized a covert
rescue mission inside the Capitol.
I am pleased to announce
that the Victors have been liberated!
Let this day mark an historic change.
With The Mockingjay
and the Victors beside us,
we have sent a clear
message to the Capitol.
That we will never again endure injustice.
Today, a day on which we reunited family,
friends, and loved ones.
Let all of Panem come together.
Not to battle
for the amusement of the Capitol.
But to join hands in this fight.
Let today be the day we promise
never to give up, never to give in
until we have made a new Panem,
where leaders are elected,
not imposed upon us.
And where the districts are free
to share the fruits of their labors
and not fight one another for scraps!
This new Panem is on the horizon.
But we must take it for ourselves.
The road there
leads through the sharp mountains
and deep ravines of District 2.
There in the heart of Panem's
steepest mountain range lies
the Capitol's principal military facility.
We can conquer this stronghold
because we are one people,
one army, one voice.
Because today is our new beginning.
Today we have freed the Victors.
Tomorrow, Panem!
Hoorah! Hoorah! Hoorah!